GARY BURNER

Philadelphia, PA 19145 | (412) 518-2935 | grburner@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/grburner Portfolio: https://personal-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Summary

Recently graduated from the University of Pennsylvania's Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp. After gaining unique experiences in multiple industries over the past 8 years it became clear that web development and data analysis best fit my skillset and passion for always learning. The last 6 months have been a deep dive into the MERN stack and programming fundamentals with a focus on teamwork in a remote environment and creative problem solving. Now I am searching for a development role that allows me to help develop simple and efficient solutions to complex problems involving process improvement, data visualization, and intuitive user interfaces.

Technical Skills

- JavaScript
- React
- Express
- MongoDB

- SQL
- AWS
- ECommerce
- Data Collection and Analysis

Projects

- DiBruno Retailer Dash | React, AMCharts, SQL, AWS | https://project-2-group1.herokuapp.com/7
 - My current employer uses older methods for data visualization and reporting. DiBruno Retailer Dash provides a solution to better visualize data and make informed purchasing decisions.
- WineHub | React, Passport, Heroku, MongoDB | https://vast-river-22849.herokuapp.com/
 - The final project for LPS involved creating a market place to allow brick and mortar wine shops to list their items for sale and connects them to consumers.
- Google Books Search | React, Bootstrap, External APIs | https://googlebooks15.herokuapp.com/
 - My first Full Stack MERN app. It allows users to easily query the Google Books API, save favorite books and delete books from their reading list.

Experience

Wine Specialist & Department Lead

Feb 2018 - Current

DiBruno Brothers

Philadelphia, PA

- Exceeded planned revenue by an average of 23% each month while managing all aspects of the department
- Increased month over month revenue while navigating structural and operations changes due to COVID
- Led a small but effective team of 3 wine specialists

Publisher Manager - 50onRed & Tiller Red Spark Jan 2016 - Feb 2018

Philadelphia, PA

- Developed new and maintained existing publisher relationships, representing \$12MM (100% of total supply) on 50onRed's publisher platform
- Onboarded new publishers to generate a 9.41% revenue increase while managing 50onRed's publishers
- Improved communication between sales and technical teams for smoother implementations of new products and publisher onboarding
- Implemented an ERP system to connect sales, finance, management and the development team.

Co Owner, COO

Oct 2014 - Jan 2016

Food Underground

Philadelphia, PA

Treasury Sales Analyst

Jun 2012 - Feb 2015

PNC Bank

Philadelphia, PA

- Attained a comprehensive understanding of PNC's products and designed technical sales presentations to depict revenue and operational impacts
- Worked closely with the Treasury Consulting Group to develop and implement complex solutions for custom projects.
- Coordinated client centric sales strategies to assist in exceeding our region's goal of \$5MM in new revenue

Education

University of Pennsylvania | LPS Coding Bootcamp Certificate *Pennsylvania State University* | Bachelor of Science: Finance

May – Oct 2020 May 2008 - May 2012